Previously on "Transformers Prime"...
在上一集里
Shockwave... I thought you'd perished on Cybertron.
震荡波 我以为你已经在塞博特恩阵亡了
The patch failed to yield any new information on the whereabouts of the Autobots.
接入器没能取得任何关于汽车人行踪的新信息
I' d know the hum of that engine anywhere.
不管在哪里 我都听得出这引擎声！
Jackie!
老千！
We can't just give up!
我们不能就这么放弃了！
Then tell me what we can do!
那么你告诉我 我们还能做什么！
We know Starscream had access to a groundbridge.
我们知道红蜘蛛在其单独行动期间 使用过环陆桥
He'd clearly been using the Harbinger.
他利用了霸天虎的废弃飞船 先驱号
It could be full of Cybertronian tech.
那上面可能装满了各种塞博特恩资源
Resources won't be of much use,
物资再多又能怎么样
not without someone to lead us.
如果没有人来…领导我们
The Forge.
…铸锤
If you had the Forge, you could fix yourself up!
如果你有了卓天越之锤 就能自我修复了
Meet Ultra Magnus.
来见见通天晓
I present to you, my liege,
很荣幸向您展示 我的君王
the ultimate Autobot hunter.
终极汽车人猎手！
A Predacon.
巨狰狞！
They've been extinct since the beginning of Cybertronian history.
他们不是在史前塞博特恩就已经灭绝了吗！
Indeed.
的确
But the specimen you see before you was bred in the laboratory,
但你眼前的样本是在实验室中培育的
cloned from fossilized remains, which I discovered on Cybertron.
是由我在塞博特恩挖掘出的化石克隆而来
Shockwave, it does my spark good to see you once again tampering with creation.
震荡波 能再次见到你的旷世杰作令我非常愉悦
Master, please! Keep your distance!
主人 请不要靠得太近！
No need for alarm. The beast is completely under my control.
无须紧张 这头野兽已完全在我的掌控之中
Such primal magnificence.
好个原始而雄壮的力量！
A sample of Energon, from Wheeljack, spilled during the Autobot's failed interrogation.
这是千斤顶受审时溢出的汽车人能量液样本
Let the hunt begin.
那么 开始狩猎吧…
Guys, you know I'm all for blowin' the scrap outta stuff,
伙计们 把那些破烂轰上天我完全没意见
but what does flattening a Decepticon mine have to do with getting the band back together and taking down Megatron?
但炸平一个虎子的能量矿 对我们重组乐队或干掉威震天有帮助吗？
Simple. When we light up this place, the blast'll be big and unmistakable.
答案很简单 这里被引爆时一定是火光冲天
Any Autobot within 500 klicks will see the sky glowin' with Energon, and come runnin'.
五百公里内的汽车人 都会注意到爆炸的光芒并尽快赶来的
Then bring the rain.
那就动手吧！
Mainframe's up and running.
主机已经运转起来了
But I'll need help hacking the operating codes.
不过我需要你帮忙破译它的操作代码
Even if the groundbridge proves functional,
就算环陆桥能够正常运转
it will be next to worthless without a means of pinpointing the current locations of our compatriots.
无法锁定其他汽车人的坐标也是枉然
Use your head, Bumblebee.
动动脑子 大黄蜂
If the Decepticons had the ability to track Autobot signals,
如果霸天虎能追踪汽车人的信号
we'd have all been at Megatron's mercy here on Earth a long time ago.
那我们早就被威震天一网打尽了
Ah... Back where we started.
唉…功亏一篑
But not if I can reconfigure these Decepticon frequencies.
未必 如果我能调整这里的信息频率
At the very least, we may be able to access their comm-link.
或许我们能够使用虎子的通讯链
No one's seen or heard from you since Cybertron went dark.
塞博特恩沦陷以后 就没人再见过你
How did you find your way to Earth?
你是怎么到达地球的？
Soldier, we may not be on Cybertron,
士兵 虽然我们已不在塞博特恩
but military protocol remains.
但是军事条例依旧有效
My apologies, Sir.
很抱歉 长官
Sir?
长官？
Advise the native life-form to watch its tone as well.
知会本地生命形态注意他的语气
What? Who is this guy?
什么？这谁啊？
Ultra Magnus was Optimus' key Lieutenant during the war back on Cybertron.
通天晓是塞博特恩战争时期 擎天柱的首席副官
Very "by the book". Just go with it.
极端教条主义 千万别顶撞他
As for your broader question,
对于你的问题
my story is that of all Autobots since the exodus.
我的经历和其他汽车人大同小异
I wandered the spaceways in search of others,
在被迫撤离家园以后 我徘徊在宇宙中搜寻同胞
reuniting with some,
但仅有少数人能够与我重聚
often only to see them fall at the hands of the Decepticons.
更多的时候我只能眼看着他们惨遭霸天虎的毒手
Until you detected the Omega beam, and followed it here.
直到你接收到终极之光并跟随它来到这里
If you are referring to the massive energy burst originating from Cybertron,
如果你指的是由塞博特恩发射出的高强度能量束
that would be affirmative.
那么你说对了
Upon my arrival, it became evident that this planet had been invaded.
当到达这个星球时 我发现它已然遭到霸天虎的入侵
My scanners also detected Autobot life signals,
但我的扫描器也同时探测到了多个汽车人的生命信号
yours being in closest proximity to my position.
而你们是距离我最近的
Signals? As in plural?
多个信号？
Sir.
长官
Five total.
总数五名
Out of seven.
但我们有七名汽车人
Jack, that doesn't necessarily mean what you're thinking.
杰克 别一下子把事情往最坏处想
Autobot signals can't be detected when they're shielded.
没被探测到的信号 很可能是被什么东西屏蔽了
Cozy little place you built for yourself, Megatron.
小堡垒建得蛮舒适的嘛 威震天
Finding the Forge in there may take awhile.
找锤子估计要花些时间了
Then, again,
或者说…
maybe you still keep your valuables in the usual place.
你仍会把贵重的东西藏在你的老地方…
I won't let you down, Optimus.
我不会让你失望的 擎天柱
I'm sorry, "overreacting?"
啥 我小题大做？
Easy for you to say, Knockout.
你说得倒轻巧 击倒！
Nobody here wants your post.
这里可没人想抢你的职位
I, on the other hand, hold the most coveted position within the Decepticon ranks.
而我就不同了 我身处所有霸天虎都梦寐以求的位置上
And no matter what he may claim,
不管震荡波嘴上怎么说
I know that Shockwave is plotting to usurp me!
但我知道他心里一直在盘算着篡我的权！
Did you see the smug look in his eye
当他给威震天陛下展示那头野兽时
when he unveiled that vile beast to lord Megatron?
你瞧他那副小人得志的嘴脸！
You don't scare me, ugly.
我可不怕你 丑八怪！
Hello, beautiful.
你在这儿呢 美人儿！
Munitions planted.
炸药放置完毕
Let's get this party started.
好戏这就开场了
Company.
有人来了！
Megatron?
威震天？
Nah. Bigger.
不 是个更大的
And I don't remember seeing that move in buckethead's repertoire.
我不记得铁桶头的马戏团里有这个小丑
A dragon?
龙？
Where'd the 'Cons get a dragon?
虎子什么时候弄到一条龙？
- What's a dragon?
- 龙是什么？
Giant flying fire-breathing lizard.
会飞会喷火的大蜥蜴！
Bulkhead, you okay?
隔板 你没事吧？
Easy, I may be hot to the touch.
小心烫手 我可是刚出炉的
Why isn't it coming after us?
它怎么不追我们了？
Lookin' for me, beast?
怪物 找我呢？
I'm right here.
老子在此！
We're gonna need more firepower!
我们需要更强大的火力！
Good thing I know just where to find some!
那你算找对人了！
Incoming!
敌军来袭！
Autobots!
是汽车人！
And the walls came tumblin' down.
这下还不活埋了它
Yes! Snuff the tragic dragon!
没错！闷死那条该死的龙！
We're toast.
这下玩完了！
One of ours?
我们的人？
Does it matter?
是又怎样？
- Jack! - Arcee!
- 杰克！ - 阿尔茜！
Miko. Can't breathe.
神子 我喘不过气了
Weakling.
真是阿弱！
Thanks for the save.
谢谢你的援手
Thank the Commander.
要谢就谢指挥官吧
Soldiers.
战士们
You?
是你？
Ultra Magnus? It's an honor.
通天晓？很荣幸见到您
It's an honor, Sir.
要说 很荣幸见到您 “长官”！
Guess blowin' that mine made us pretty easy to spot.
是我制造的大爆炸把你们引来的吧
Ultra Magnus already had a bead on your signals,
通天晓已经追踪到你们的信号了
and ours.
还有我们的
Care to tell us what exactly's nipping at our tailpipes?
介不介意解释一下那只跟屁虫到底是什么东西？
We think it's a robot dragon.
我们觉得那是一只机器龙
Or a Cybertronian reptile.
或者是某种塞博特恩爬行动物
Brace yourselves.
全员注意！
It's right on top of us.
那家伙就在我们头顶
What is it now, lord Megatron?
又有何贵干？ 威震天“陛下”
Agent Fowler, it's Ratchet!
福勒探员 我是救护车
Ratchet? Where's Jack? Is he with you?
救护车 杰克在哪儿？和你在一起吗？
No, he is not.
不 他没和我在一起
Listen, we don't have much time.
听着 我们时间有限
I have taken a tremendous, yet calculated, risk in contacting you.
我正冒着无法估算的巨大风险和你联系
Hopefully, the Decepticons are not monitoring their own frequencies as closely as they no doubt are those of the humans.
希望虎子们没有疯狂地监控自己的通讯系统
I am transmitting our current coordinates.
我现在把我们当前的坐标发送给你…
What?
什么？
Ratchet, have you heard from anyone else?
救护车 你有其他人的消息吗？
What about Prime?
擎天柱怎么样了？
It's one of ours!
是汽车人的飞船
Raf!
拉夫！
Girl's got a grip, doesn't she?
这丫头的劲儿不小吧？
You're alive.
你们都还活着！
Ultra Magnus?
通天晓！
Doctor.
医官
What a grave disappointment this must be for you, master.
您一定大失所望吧 主人
And to make matters worse,
而更糟的是
because it cannot speak, we have no way of knowing why the Predacon failed so miserably.
由于巨狰狞言语不能 我们无法得知它为何失败得如此彻底
Poor, mute, mindless creature.
可怜的生物 又蠢又哑…
New paint job looks good, Bee.
新喷涂看起来不错嘛 小蜂
At least you had something to work with.
看来你很能自娱自乐嘛
If I reversed my colors, I'd be pink.
如果换我的话 我一定会选粉色！
The communications link needs further calibration to be compatible with Autobot frequencies.
我仍需进一步调校通信链 让它兼容汽车人的频率
The groundbridge, however, is fully operational.
但环陆桥已经可以正常运转了
That would've come in handy when robo-dragon was trying to eat us for breakfast.
这样逃跑就方便多了 等那只机器龙把我们当早餐吃的时候
The indigenous population of this planet, do they all display the same disregard for authority?
这个星球的土著都这样目无纪律吗？
No. Mostly just Miko.
不 基本上只有神子而已
No! Don't shoot!
不 别开枪！
It's Fowler. He's with us!
那是福勒 他是我们这边的！
It's okay, mom. I'm fine.
没事了 妈妈 我很好
Your families are safe.
你的家人很安全
Agent Fowler saw to it that Jasper was evacuated in time.
福勒探员已经确保贾斯帕被及时疏散了
The only signals Ultra Magnus was able to isolate are standing right here.
通天晓所能识别的信号都在这里了
Maybe his scanner's faulty.
可能他的扫描器出故障了
So the kid's unaccounted for.
这么说 烟幕小子仍然下落不明
Smokescreen bridged out unaccompanied.
当虎子进攻时 烟幕被环陆桥传送走了
Only Optimus knows where.
只有擎天柱知道目的地
And Optimus remained behind,
当时擎天柱留下断后
to destroy the groundbridge, to ensure that everyone else... made it to safety.
他破坏了环陆桥 以确保每个人都安全撤离
I watched the base go down.
我…亲眼见到基地被摧毁
No one or thing walked out of there.
没有任何人或东西走出来
Not that we could see.
或许只是我们没看到
Even if Prime survived,
即使擎天柱幸存下来了
I'm not sure we can afford to wait for him to show up.
我们也不能在这里坐等他的出现
Not with Megatron holding our planet hostage
尤其是威震天正趾高气昂地守在他的黑山老窝
from his high and mighty perch at Darkmount.
并将我们整个星球挟为人质
I would be inclined to agree with the native life-form.
我倾向于本地生命形态的意见
We must stop Megatron,
我们必须阻止威震天
with or without Optimus Prime.
无论擎天柱在与不在
Optimus!
擎天柱
I have The Forge.
我拿到卓天越之锤了
You can use it to repair yourself!
你可以用它来修复自己！
That is not the reason I had you retrieve the relic.
这并非我让你取回这个圣物的本意
What? I don't understand.
什么？我不明白
The power of the Forge is not unlimited.
卓天越之锤的力量 并非无穷无尽
Its energy has already begun to ebb.
它的能量已接近干涸
So it's running low, who cares?
它的能量是弱了些 那有什么关系！
All we need is enough juice to get you back into fighting shape!
只要能把你治好就足够了！
Whatever power remains must be used to rebuild the Omega lock,
它残余的能量必须用于修复终极之锁
to restore Cybertron.
以复苏塞博特恩
But that would mean...
但那就意味着…
The fate of all our kind is more vital... than that of any one of us.
我们种族的延续比我们任何一员的生命都更为重要…
... Including me.
…也包括我在内
We must do everything in our power to ensure Megatron's downfall,
我们必须竭尽所能 以推翻威震天的统治
but we will need to be smart about it.
而此事只能智取
Whoa, who put shoulderpads in command?
喔 是谁让这个垫肩男当家的？
Temporary command.
临时当家而已
Ultra Magnus is the only logical choice.
通天晓是唯一合乎逻辑的人选
He was trained by Optimus
他曾在擎天柱麾下受训
and served as his commanding officer throughout the War For Cybertron.
并在塞博特恩之战时一直担任领导职位
Now, unless there is any further objection,
如果没有其他人提出反对意见的话
soldier, please, follow me.
战士们 跟我来
Aye aye, Cap'n.
遵命 头儿
Autobots.
汽车人们
Take your pick.
挑件趁手的家伙吧！
Now you're speaking my language,
现在你合我胃口了
Sir.
长官！
Optimus, the Forge is a relic of the Primes.
擎天柱 卓天越之锤是领袖的圣物
We can't use it to restore Cybertron, not without a Prime. Not without you.
没有领袖 没有您 我们无法用它复苏塞博特恩！
There will be a new Prime.
会有一位新领袖站出来的！
You can worry about that after we get you patched up, and we take down Megatron.
我们先把您治好 同时干掉威震天 然后再操心新领袖吧
The time for a new leader is upon us.
新领袖诞生的时刻已然到来！
In my spark...
以我火种之名
I believe that leader... stands before me right now.
我坚信他此刻就站在我的面前！